When positioning children relative to other sibling views,
children을 sibling[형제] 뷰들과 관련되게 위치시킬 때
you can add constraints on their position.
당신은 그들에게 제한을 둘 수 있어요.
For example, one TextView must be above another TextView,
예를 들어, 하나의 텍스트 뷰가 다른 텍스트 뷰 아래에 와야 한다거나
or one ImageView must be to the left of another TextView.
한 이미지 뷰는 반드시 텍스트 뷰의 오른쪽에 와야 해요.
All these constraints remind me of making a seating chart for
이 모든 제한은 저녁 파티를 위한 좌석 배치도를 만드는 것을
a dinner party.
생각나게 하네요.
We do have our birthday party celebration coming up, so
우리 생일 파티 축하가 다가오고 있으니
let's look at the seating chart for that.
그 좌석 배치를 봅시다.
We invited all these people over for
우리는 이 사람들을 저녁 식사에 초대했지만
dinner But there are constraints on where people want to sit.
사람들이 앉고 싶어하는 자리에는 제한이 있어요.
Some people must sit next to their best friend.
몇 사람들은 그들의 제일 친한 친구 옆에 앉아야 해요.
Other people have what you might call frenemies.
다른 사람들은 친한 적군이라 불리는 이들을 갖고 있죠.
So, they might not want to sit next to certain people.
그래서 그들은 특정 사람들 옆에 앉고 싶지 않아 해요.
So, taking into account all of that, I came up with this proposed layout.
그래서 이 모든 것을 고려할 때 이 제안된 레이아웃이 떠오릅니다.
Kunal, Ben, and Kagure are up here.
Kunal, Ben, Kagure가 여기 있죠.
Natalie, Lyla, and me are down here And Amy, Omoju and Jenny are in this corner.
Natalie, Lyla와 제가 여기 있고 Amy, Omoju, Jennie는 여기 있어요.
So could we build this seating arrangement in XML using TextViews and
텍스트 뷰와 relative layout을 이용해 이 자리 배치를 XML에서
a relative layout?
만들 수 있을까요?
We know how to position views in corners.
우리는 구석에 뷰를 위치시키는 법을 알아요.
So the Lyla TextView would be aligned to the parent's left edge and bottom edge.
Lyla 텍스트 뷰는 parent의 왼쪽 아래 모서리에 정렬이 됩니다.
The Jennie TextView would be aligned to the parent's right edge and bottom edge.
Jennie 텍스트 뷰는 parent의 오른쪽 아래 모서리에 위치해요.
For Ben we would align them to the top edge of the parent.
Ben을 parent의 위쪽에 위치시키고 싶어요.
By the way, we're assuming that the parent is the full width and
그런데 parent가 화면의 전체 높이와 너비를 차지한다고 가정해요.
So back to Ben.
Ben으로 돌아와서,
He's aligned to the top of the parent.
그는 parent의 최상단에 있어요.
We also want to center him horizontally.
그를 수평에서 가운데로 정렬하고 싶어요.
And formerly, you might call these three views the anchor views.
이전에 당신은 이 세 뷰를 anchor 뷰라고 불렀어요.
Because everyone else is positioned relative to these people.
다른 모든 것은 다른 사람들과 연관되어 위치해있기 때문입니다.
And these people won't move, regardless of where everyone else is sitting.
다른 모든이들이 어디 앉건 이 사람들은 움직이지 않아요.
So let's add another person.
다른 사람을 하나 더 추가합시다.
We have Kunal here, who's located to the left of Ben.
여기 Kunal이 Ben의 왼쪽에 위치해 있어요.
But how do we express that in XML?
그것을 XML에서 어떻게 표현할까요?
Well, there's no specific attribute that says that a view should be to the left
Ben 뷰의 왼쪽에 뷰가 와야한다는 특정한 속성은 없어요.
that it works for any use case that you'd want.
그래서 당신이 원하는 모든 사용 유형에서 작동하죠.
We want to position Kunal to the left of Ben, but
우리는 Kunal을 Ben의 왼쪽에 위치시키고 싶어요.
we don't know of any existing attribute names that can do that.
하지만 그것을 할 수 있는 기존 속성 이름을 모르죠.
Luckily though,
하지만 운 좋게도
RelativeLayout has an attribute that says android: layout_toLeftof.
RelativeLayout의 속성은, android:layout_toLeftOf,
This means that the Kunal text view should be to the left of some view.
이것은 Kunal 텍스트 뷰가 어떤 뷰의 왼쪽에 온다는 것을 뜻해요.
And the way that we specify some view is to use view IDs.
어떤 뷰를 특정짓는 방법은 뷰 ID를 사용하는 겁니다.
We can assign view ID names to any view.
어떤 뷰에든 뷰 ID를 할당할 수 있죠.
They don't have to be specifically addressed for RelativeLayout.
그것들은 RelativeLayout을 위해 특별히 사용될 필요 없어요.
They could be located within a RelativeLayout, or a LinearLayout, or
그것들은 RelativeLayout, LinearLayout, 다른 뷰 그룹
any other view group.
안에 존재할 수 있어요.
So on the Ben TextView, we can add this attribute, android:id.
Ben 텍스트 뷰에서 android:id 속성을 추가해요.
The value of it is the ID name.
값은 이것의 ID 이름입니다.
The format starts with @ symbol, @ refers to a resource in our Android app.
형식은 @로 시작하고 @는 안드로이드 앱의 자료를 참조하죠.
We've also seen this @symbol for referring to images in our app.
우리 앱의 이미지를 참조할 때 @ 기호를 보았죠.
For example app Drawable.
@drawable이 그 예였죠.
Then we specify the resource type.
그리고 자료 종류를 특정지어요.
In this case, the resource type is an id.
이 경우에 자료 종류는 ID입니다.
This is the name that we chose for the Ben TextView.
이것은 우리가 선택한 Ben 텍스트 뷰의 이름입니다.
We call it ben_text_view.
이것은 ben_text_view라 불리죠.
The basic requirements are that the name can't have any spaces.
기본 조건에 따르면 이름이 공백을 가지면 안 됩니다.
That's why we use underscore symbols here.
여기 _ 기호를 사용한 이유죠.
Numbers are fine though.
숫자는 괜찮아요.
So in this case we give Ben the ID of ben_text_view.
이 경우 ben_text_view라는 아이디를 Ben에게 줬어요.
That way we can refer to it later.
그러면 나중에 이를 참조해도 됩니다.
So on the Kunal TextView we can add the attribute layout_toLeftof and
Kunal 텍스트 뷰에 속성 layout_toLeftOf를 추가해요.
we can say it's to the left of the Ben TextView.
이것은 Ben 텍스트 뷰의 왼쪽에 있다고 말할 수 있죠.
We refer to the ID for the Ben TextView using @id.
@id를 사용하여 Ben 텍스트 뷰의 ID를 참조합시다.
We don't need to use the plus symbol because We've already defined that ID.
이미 그 ID를 정의했으니 + 기호는 사용하지 않습니다.
This is the second time we're using the ID.
이 ID를 두 번째로 사용하는 거죠.
When you come up with view ID names, make sure that they're all unique names.
뷰 ID 이름을 생각해냈다면 그게 모두 특정한 이름이 되게 하세요.
Usually, picking something related to the content inside of it is helpful.
보통 안의 요소와 관련된 것을 고르는 것이 도움됩니다.
Okay, cool, so that's how you position Kunal to the left of Ben.
좋아요, 그렇게 Kunal을 Ben의 왼쪽에 놓습니다.
Now, say, for example, we want to position Omoju above Jennie.
예를 들어, 이제 Omoju를 Jennie의 위에 두고 싶어요.
Since we're going to need to refer to Jennie,
Jennie를 참조해야 하기 때문에
we should create an ID for Jennie.
우리는 Jennie의 ID를 만들어야 해요.
On the Jennie TextView, we specify this attribute and give it this value.
Jennie 텍스트 뷰에서 속성을 특정짓고 이에 값을 줘요.
The ID name is jennie_text_view.
ID 이름은 jennie_text_view입니다.
On the Omoju TextView, we add this attribute.
Omoju 텍스트 뷰에 이 속성을 추가합니다.
This says that Omoju should be positioned above the jennie_text_view.
이것은 Omoju가 jennie_text_view의 위에 와야 한다고 말합니다.
And this is the ID that we created up here.
이것은 우리가 여기서 만든 ID예요.
Let's look at the XML layout.
XML 레이아웃을 봅시다.
We have a relative layout where the width and height are match_parent.
너비와 높이가 match_parent인 RelativeLayout이 있어요.
Then we have the lyla_text_view.
그래고 Lyla 텍스트 뷰가 있고
It's aligned to the parent's bottom left corner, and
이것은 parent의 아래 왼쪽에 정렬되어 있어서
that's what we see down here.
여기 아래에 이렇게 보입니다.
Then we have the jennie_text_view.
또 Jennie 텍스트 뷰가 있어요.
It's aligned to the parents bottom right corner.
이것은 parent의 아래 오른쪽에 있어요.
So that's over here.
그건 여기 있네요.
Then we have the ben_text_view.
그리고 Ben 텍스트 뷰가 있어요.
And it's aligned to the top edge of the parent.
이것은 parent의 위쪽 모서리에 정렬되어 있죠.
It's also centered horizontally.
또한 수평에서 가운데에 있죠.
These are the anchor views and
이것들은 anchor 뷰들이고
now we can position the other views around them.
우리는 다른 뷰들을 이것 주변에 놓을 수 있어요.
Notice that for each of the views I already went ahead and added an ID.
각 뷰들은 이미 지나왔고 ID를 추가했어요.
So this is the Ben TextView ID.
이것은 Ben 텍스트 뷰의 ID예요.
Then we can position the Kunal TextView to the left of Ben.
우리는 Kunal 텍스트 뷰를 Ben의 왼쪽에 둘 수 있어요.
I use the view ID for Ben right here.
여기에 Ben의 뷰 ID를 사용해요.
Then we position the Omoju TextView above Jenny.
그리고 Omoju 텍스트 뷰를 Jennie의 위에 위치시켜요.
Omoju is aligned to the right edge of the parent, and
Omoju는 parent의 오른쪽에 정렬되었고
above the Jenny TextView.
Jennie 텍스트 뷰의 위에 정렬되었죠.
Okay cool.
좋아요.
So there's more friends to position correctly in this layout.
이 레이아웃에서 바르게 배치시킬 친구들이 더 많아요.
In the instructor notes below we've provided you a link
아래 instructor notes에 초기 코드가 쓰여진
to the XML Visualizer with some initial code already in there.
XML 비주얼라이저로 가는 링크를 제공하겠습니다.
Go ahead and modify the XML so
가서 XML을 수정하세요.
that we can achieve this desired layout for everyone.
모두를 위해 원하는 레이아웃을 만드세요.
Some of the views are already positioned incorrectly, so
어떤 뷰는 이미 잘못된 위치에 정렬되어 있으므로
you'll need to fix those.
그것들을 고쳐야 합니다.
By the way, we just introduced a ton of new attributes.
그런데 우리는 많은 새로운 속성을 소개해드렸어요.
But don't feel like you have to memorize all of them.
하지만 그것 모두를 기억해야 한다고 생각하지 마세요.
You can always look them up at any time.
언제든 그것들을 찾아볼 수 있어요.
You can just search for a relativelayout, layout params.
RelativeLayout.LayoutParams를 검색해볼 수 있어요.
If you click on this first link, you go to the documentation for this.
첫 링크를 클릭하면 이를 위한 문서로 연결됩니다.
So these are all the XML attributes that you can put on a child view
이것들은 RelativeLayout 안의 child 뷰에 넣을 수 있는
within a RelativeLayout so that the RelativeLayout knows how to lay it out.
XML 속성들이고, RelativeLayout이 어떻게 정렬할지 알려줍니다.
Here are some that you're already familiar with.
이미 친숙할 법한 것들이 있는데,
Layout_above, alignParentbottom, alignParentright and so on.
layout_above, alignParentBottom, alignParentRight 등등
Note that for
알려두건대
teaching purposes, the XML Visualizer may not support all of these attributes.
XML 비주얼라이저는 이 모든 속성들을 지원하지 않습니다.
However, when you're developing an app in Android Studio you
하지만 Android Studio에서 당신의 앱을 개발할 때
should be able to use all of these.
이 모든 것들을 사용할 수 있죠.